MEGHANA KANDRU TECHNICAL WRITER, DATA ENGINEERING AT AMAZON

meghanakandru2412@gmail.com Explore my work: <u>GitHub Portfolio</u>

LinkedIn

SUMMARY

Experienced Technical Writer with a data engineering background, skilled in creating documentation that bridges the gap between development teams, stakeholders, and end-users. Authored 100+ comprehensive user guides, technical manuals, and training materials enhancing project success for global teams.

EDUCATION

Northeastern University Sep 2019 - Aug 2021

Master of Science in Information Systems GPA: 3.91/4.0

Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University, India Sep 2013 - April 2017

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering GPA: 3.76/4.0

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Writing Tools : Markdown, LaTex, MadCap Flare, Adobe FrameMaker

• Programming Languages: SQL,PL/SQL,Python,UNIX shell scripting

AWS Services
Redshift,S3,AWS Glue,AppFlow,CloudWatch,IAM,Secrets Manager,RDS
Database/Storage
Microsoft SQL Server,Oracle MySQL,PostgreSQL,NoSQL-MongoDB,HBase

• Operating System : Red hat Enterprise Linux, Ubuntu, Windows, OSX

• Certifications : Salesforce Platform App Builder, Administrator, Platform Developer 1, Google

Developers - Technical Writing One and Two

• Other Tools : Git, Jira, Microsoft Office, Tableau, Salesforce, Share Point, Power BI, Service Now

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Technical Writer, Data Engineering at Amazon

Oct 2021 - Present

- Author comprehensive documentation for ETL pipelines, data formats (XML, JSON) and AWS services
- Develop user guides and technical manuals for internal tools and processes
- Conduct knowledge-sharing sessions and created training materials for new hires
- Design and implement scalable ETL pipelines, including data inspection, cleansing, transformation, and modeling using AWS Services
- Develop and optimize SQL queries, boosting Redshift performance by 80% and automate data processes using Python

Data Analyst, Technical Writer Intern at Zeevo Group

Feb 2021 – July 2021

- Documented reports, dashboards, and data analysis processes using PowerBI
- Wrote technical guides on SQL queries, data auditing, and automation techniques
- Developed automated workflows and step-by-step procedures using Microsoft Power Automate
- Analyzed flight data using SQL queries, joins and triggers across multiple databases for auditing

Graduate Teaching Assistant at Northeastern University

Sep 2020 - Dec 2020

- Assisted in creating course materials and tutorials for Data Management and Database Design, while providing feedback to students
- · Conducted weekly tutoring sessions, guiding students and assessing their progress to reinforce key concepts

Data Analyst, Technical Writer at Cognizant Technology Solutions

May 2018 - Aug 2019

- Integrated Salesforce with Qualtrics to build surveys using configurations, customizations, HTML, CSS & JS
- Performed response mapping and retrieved records using SOQL(like SQL). Automated survey data collection and analysis with a workflow rule, reducing survey creation and feedback analysis time by 85%
- Authored detailed technical documentation, user guides and training materials for system integration, data retrieval, and automation processes

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Big Data Analysis of Book Crossing (MongoDB, Hadoop, Pig, HiveQL, Mahout, PowerBI) December 2020

- Analyzed the dataset by using MapReduce filtering, organization, secondary sorting and chaining techniques
- Documented and built a book recommendation system utilizing MongoDB, Hadoop, Pig, HiveQL and HBase

Resort Management System (SQL, DDL, Microsoft SSMS, PowerBI)

May 2020 - August 2020

- Led a team of 4 to design a normalized ERD, implement a secure relational database with triggers, constraints, and encrypted columns
- Authored technical documentation on database design, security features, and visualization techniques